Mehrdad Qasemkhani

DevOps Engineer

qasemkhani.mehrdad@gmail.com

+989385200818

linkedin.com/in/gasemkhani-mehrdad

https://mehrdad-drpc.github.io/

Summary

Experienced DevOps Engineer high focus on Infrastructure as Code, with a demonstrated history of working in the cloud industry.

Skilled in SQL and NoSQL Databases. Functional and Object-Oriented Programming.

Linux and ShellScripting, DevOps tools. Some TCP/IP protocols.

Strong engineering professional who graduated from Shamsipour and Raja university.

Experience



DevOps Engineer

Spara Security Group

May 2021 - Present (1 year 5 months +)

- Automate Build and Deploy Spara PAM Security Module CI/CD via Bamboo
- Dockerize Spara PAM Security Module
- Maintain core businesses production(PAM)
- Full CI/CD via Attlasian Bamabo and Ansible (old service)
- Dockerize PAM Modules
- Log gathering via Elastic and Kibana
- Produce and Consume messages via RabbitMQ
- Synchronize Postgresql via Bucardo Active/Passive
- High-Available PAM nodes as Active/Active
- Load-Balance HTTP and TCP traffic via haproxy
- Separate RDP/VNC, SSH, Oracle, and HTTP traffic via Keepalived on the edge of the PAM network
- Infrastructure as Code IaC full automation via Ansible

DevOps Engineer

Respina Networks & Beyond

Feb 2020 - Apr 2021 (1 year 3 months)

- Cloud Telecommunication Technology CPaaS, UCaaS
- Session Initiation Protocol
- Kamailio SIP-Server
- Asterisk/Freeswitch Softswitch
- Maintainer of own SIP-Trunk
- Maintainer of own Cloud HostedPBX
- SIP/HTTP Load Balancing
- High Availability
- Virtual Router Redundancy Protocol
- Docker/Docker-Compose
- Develop ARI(Asterisk RESTful Interface) with Python and Django
- Develop Asterisk Call App Manager Over The ARI with pure Python
- Automate all deploying process with CI/CD

• Automate configuration management, and application-deployment via Ansible

Backend Developer

Respina Networks & Beyond

Jun 2019 - Feb 2020 (9 months)

- Develop ARI(Asterisk RESTful Interface) with python and Django
- Develop Asterisk Call Manager Over The ARI with pure python

Python Developer

Kara Tadbir Hooshmand Kish

Jul 2017 - Jun 2018 (1 year)

• Analyzed, designed and developed of a RESTful API with Python, Flask, gREST and Neo4j,

PostgreSQL, Kong, ... to serve 2.5 million subscribers

- Experienced with pair-programming of project with junior/senior developers
- Hands-on experience with many of the latest cutting-edge technologies
- Provided regular and effective progress updates to my-head
- Write some python's unit-test and integration-test to develop CI/CD



C Developer

AVA Communication Industries Co.

Sep 2016 - Jan 2017 (5 months)

As a fresh graduated programmer we were developer of some applications and tools over the SIP protocol(Session Initiation Protocol). I wrote some part of these project with C and JS high focus on websocket programming.

Education



Shamsipour Technical and Vocational College

Associate's Degree, Copmuter 2009 - 2011

Raja

Bachelor of Science (BS) 2011 - 2013

Licenses & Certifications



Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA) - Fanavaran Anisa

ILH259910098099

Skills

Infrastructure as code (IaC) • DevOps • Kubernetes • Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) • Programming • High Availability • OOP • Software Development • Shell Scripting • Linux